<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">    <title>decafbad recaffinated</title>    <link rel="self" href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/index.atom"/>    <updated>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 16:55:34 -0800</updated>    <author>        <name>l.m.orchard</name>        <email>l.m.orchard@pobox.com</email>    </author>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/index.atom</id>      <entry>    <title>Martijn Faassen</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/13/MartijnFaassen.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/13/MartijnFaassen.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-13T13:33:36-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm happy to see the hard work in the Zope community has finally started to pay off: for a change, our Zope work is actually being associated with flexible pluggable things instead of evil monolithic things. It's welcome news.</p>]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>So I couldn't resist adding comments...</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/13/SoIcouldntresistaddingco.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/13/SoIcouldntresistaddingco.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-13T00:02:49-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I basically already had the code ready from my <a href="http://blogs.opml.org/decafbad"  >OPML blog</a>, so I just adapted things a bit to integrate Haloscan comments into this thing.  I'm tempted to see if the new and shiny <a href="http://disqus.com/"  >Disqus</a> service could fit in here, but that's another day's project.</p>]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>Hello world.  Shiny new toy blog here, let's see how it works.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/12/HelloworldShinynewtoyblo.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/12/HelloworldShinynewtoyblo.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-12T11:45:18-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>Plans for this thing</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/11/Plansforthisthing.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/11/Plansforthisthing.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-11T19:39:25-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the next things I'd like to do with this blog is hook in some importing from my own feeds.  That is, give it an inbox from my myriad other accounts like <a href="http://del.icio.us/deusx"  >Delicious</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/lmorchard"  >Twitter</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/deusx/"  >Flickr</a>, etc.  Then, I can copy and tweak content items from each of those and turn them into items posted here.  </p><p>I'm wondering whether something manually massaged would work out better than just a simple automated feed blender.  Given that I'm working off and on with <a href="http://decafbad.com/trac/wiki/FeedMagick"  >FeedMagick</a>, I'll probably do that too eventually and stick that on the front page of decafbad.com.</p>]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>Hello world.  I'm trying out yet another blog.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/HelloworldImtryingoutyet.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/HelloworldImtryingoutyet.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:44:47-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog is something new for me:  After around seven years of using <a href="http://eastgate.com/Tinderbox/"  >Eastgate Tinderbox</a> for private notes, I finally sat down and spent time with its HTML export templates.  After a bit of amateur design effort and some trial and error, I've thrown together something to publish online.</p><p>This isn't entirely new, however.  I've borrowed a crapload from <a href="http://tumblr.com/"  >Tumblr</a> by building lots of templates for memes and media objects.  And, I've tried to model authoring habits after what I do with the <a href="http://support.opml.org/"  >OPML Editor</a> by centering the thing around a page-a-day and a minimum of mental cost in getting things out of my head.</p><p>Let's see how far I go with it.</p>]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>I might try doing a screencast of how I blog with this thing.  It might be interesting to someone.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Imighttrydoingascreencas.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Imighttrydoingascreencas.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:43:50-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>The feeds are probably invalid around here.  Still got kinks to work out.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Thefeedsareprobablyinval.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Thefeedsareprobablyinval.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:04:07-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>I'm also trying to decide whether this thing needs comments.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Imalsotryingtodecidewhet.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Imalsotryingtodecidewhet.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:06:07-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>Still Alive</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/StillAlive.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/StillAlive.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:43:13-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a great song from the ending of Portal, excellent for trying out my inline audio player.</p>]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>As you can see, I've got a few tricks in the templates.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/AsyoucanseeIvegotafewtri.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/AsyoucanseeIvegotafewtri.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:42:31-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can drop in items especially styled for quotes, chat transcripts, images, audio files, and the occasional long-winded essay.  Eventually I hope to find a streamlined way to use each of them.</p>]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>Since I've been watching a crazy amount of Babylon 5 lately, I'll try another trick.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/SinceIvebeenwatchingacra.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/SinceIvebeenwatchingacra.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:40:25-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>Zathras</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Zathras.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Zathras.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:40:04-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everyone always coming to Zathras with problems. Great responsibilities. But Zathras does not mind. Zathras trained in crisis management.</p>]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>I think that's enough for the moment.  I'm going to try pushing this stuff to my web site.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Ithinkthatsenoughforthem.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/10/Ithinkthatsenoughforthem.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-10T23:45:50-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>Hello world.  Oh, look:  It's another day!</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/11/HelloworldOhlookItsanoth.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/11/HelloworldOhlookItsanoth.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-11T19:40:01-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wonder how much I'll actually do with this thing?</p>]]></summary>  </entry>  <entry>    <title>Good night, Tinderbox.  Good work.  Sleep well.  I'll most likely kill you in the morning.</title>    <link href="http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/12/GoodnightTinderboxGoodwo.html"/>    <id>http://decafbad.com/recaffinated/archives/2007/11/12/GoodnightTinderboxGoodwo.html</id>    <updated>2007-11-12T17:26:34-08:00</updated>    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I've been using <a href="http://eastgate.com/Tinderbox/"  >Tinderbox</a> for a number of years now.  I've used it in various capacities as an outliner, a personal idea catcher, and a book planner.  And up until now, I've been plotting constantly to kill it.</p><p>Well, maybe I shouldn't put it as seriously as that.  I've got nothing against <a href="http://eastgate.com/Tinderbox/"  >Tinderbox</a> except that it's not Open Source, it's somewhat pricey (US$229), and it's kind of a niche app (Mac-only).  </p><p>The reason these things worry me is because I'd like to avoid locking my ideas away in a proprietary box that not many people know how to open and is certain to go away someday.  As we know, <a href="http://diveintomark.org/archives/2004/05/14/freedom-0"  >in the long run, the utility of all non-Free software approaches zero.</a></p><p>But, to be honest: </p><ul><li> I've been worrying that Tinderbox would go away for probably 7 or 8 years now &mdash; it hasn't and doesn't show signs that it will any time soon.</li><li> I've gotten good use out of it for a number of years after my original license expired, using somewhat ancient versions still quite productively.</li><li> The complex user interface is powerful and yet pleasant for me to use after training myself to do so &mdash; out of all the idea management stuff I've tried to plug my brain into, Tinderbox has been the one most worth the price.</li><li> The native format of Tinderbox files is XML and not some weird binary blob.  It's a structure specific to Tinderbox, but it's clean and mungeable XML nonetheless.</li></ul><p>So, over the past years, I've been continually thinking of how to kill Tinderbox.  I've <a href="http://decafbad.com/trac/wiki/XoxoOutliner"  >built most of a JavaScript-based outliner</a>.  I've played with <a href="http://decafbad.com/blog/2005/07/02/drag-the-boxes-stretch-the-lines"  >DOM scripting to make Map views</a>.  I've started and drifted away from a dozen other things all aimed at replacing Tinderbox for myself &mdash; and they've all begun and ended in Tinderbox itself.  </p><p>I start planning them in Tinderbox, and then I eventually return to Tinderbox to plan the next one.  But never has using Tinderbox become enough of an itch to finally commit to one of them and free myself from its clutches.  And, in the mean time, I keep myself from embracing all the features of Tinderbox for fear of getting more dependent on it.</p><p>Well, I think it's time to admit that I'm already very dependent on it.  And I really like how it works, mostly.  There are a few rough edges, but only in comparison to some platonic perfect app I've got in my head that I'll never get around to writing as long as Tinderbox itself is available.</p><p>So, I've renewed my license and got up to date, and I've thrown myself finally at the documentation for the state of Tinderbox export template art.  I've gotten this start of a new blog put together, and I feel like I finally understand how this stuff works.  </p><p>The sense I've got for the fluidity of my ideas in Tinderbox has greatly increased.  My feelings of lock-in are deferred to the day when Tinderbox eventually goes away &mdash; a long time from now.  And even when Tinderbox goes away, I am comfortable enough with the data files left behind that I expect to be able to do <i>something</i> with them as long as any XML tools still exist.</p><p>In the meantime, I'm going to start finally exploring how I can take complete advantage of this crazy thing.</p>]]></summary>  </entry></feed>